How many of these head coaches do you
actually know?
>> That's a No, that's a great question. I
never thought about it. Probably more
than I thought I've worked with. Um
I I felt like yesterday was cool.
Yesterday we were kind of all at the
pool together kind of hanging out and I
didn't even know that we would do that.
But I felt like there's a lot of them
that I worked with, you know, and
probably about half of them I know
pretty well. Um, and it's, you know, I I
was in the league for such a long period
of time and then I left and then I came
back and it's only been really, this
will be year three coming back, but a
lot of those guys I was with at some
point are with a connection. So, I feel
like I know a lot of them.
>> Um, I want Malik to be himself. Um,
there's there's nothing I'm going to sit
here and say that I want this, this,
this, and this. I want Malik to come in
and be himself. I don't want him to
change um on or off the field because he
is a he's an incredible human. I think
he's got great leadership qualities that
guys will rally around. I've seen it. Um
these guys have seen it. Um and I've
seen what we can do on the field. He
needs to develop. He needs to continue
to grow. But I'm not going to I'm not
going to put any expectation on what I
want to see from him.
Why do I like him as a person? I mean,
just you guys, when you start to be
around him, you'll see it. He's humble.
He's
um got this way about him where he
connects with his teammates. It's the
way he treats people. It's the way he
works, which to me is probably more
important than anything. I just
I think the more you guys are around him
and the more he's around his teammates,
everybody will start to see it. Um, and
I'm going to be excited for you guys all
to experience that. The type of person
that he is, the type of worker that he
is, the way he'll treat the media, the
way he'll treat his teammates, and the
way he'll be with his coaches and his
teammates. So, I'm excited for you guys
to experience that.
Yeah. Um, I I'll be I'll have some fun
with this one with you. There's There's
three things when I watch a corner's
tape, when I evaluate a tape that I
always look at. There's three levels of
play that I want to see if they can win
at. One is the line of scrimmage. I call
that level one. Can he win at the line?
Can he press? Can he make a guy stop and
start his feet? Can he use his hands? Is
he quick enough to change direction?
Right? Can he take good cut off angles?
When a guy steps out and goes in, is he
fast enough to come back inside? So, can
he win there? Level two is all the
intermediate routes, right? All the inb
breaks, the digs, the comebacks. Can he
drop his hips and accelerate out of his
cuts? Or is he a high hip guy that can't
do that? And maybe he doesn't have to do
that because he can win so well to line
of scrimmage. And then level three is
can he win down the field? Can he make a
play down the field? Now, I don't know
if you're going to find many that can be
elite level one, level two, level three.
Those are the Derell Rivases of the
world and the Hall of Famers, right? Um,
and I've been fortunate enough to see
some of those guys and coach some of
those guys. But then you look to see,
can they at least do two out of the
three? And then you're then I go from
there and then it's can they do one out
of the three. If if they can't do any
out of three, then we're probably going
to have to find a different player. But
once you see what they can do, then you
can start building around the coverages
that you think you can play with those
guys. Um, and that's what I'm excited to
do. That's why I can't wait for I mean,
a week from today, our players get here,
which is all we've been waiting for as
coaches is to get around our players.
You know, we're not allowed to do too
much with them because it's going to be
phase one, but those are the things that
I'm excited to be around and I'm going
to continue to coach and get my hands on
those guys and help develop them.
Um, well, one, let me answer the first
part of your question. That's it's a
good question. Is there a free? Is there
a strong maybe? Who do we have? Do we
have a really good athlete who can run
and and cover a lot of ground? And is
the other guy a big more box guy who's
going to have to drop in? or do we have
two guys who can kind of do both, right?
And then you can play them right and
left, you can play them field boundary,
you can move them around. My last couple
years, I had guys moving all over the
place based on what their skill set was
and where we wanted to put certain
players. Um, I think at that position,
um, intelligent in intelligence and
instincts are very important for me. I
want guys who can think think on their
feet. I want guys who can kind of as I
call the game through those guys can
kind of react and communicate with me
and tell me what they see and I can kind
of play with the game within the game
with the opposing quarterbacks with
those guys. So I want guys that
understand the game, can think on their
feet because they're out there alone at
that point, have good instincts and then
you got to be a great tackler. I mean
that's that's so important. You're the
guy who's kind of like the eraser when
anything bad happens. You got to you got
to get the guy down or it's going to be
a touchdown, right? The ball can't get
behind you. And then the skill sets
after that is there's some that are
really good in man coverage, some have
really good range. Um, some are really
physical, some have all of it. Um, all
I'm looking forward to doing is getting
my hands on these guys, figuring out
what they do best, and then we'll
develop what we're going to do with
them. I'm not going to I'm not going to
walk in the first day and say, "This is
our defense. This is what the safety has
to look like, and this is how we're
playing." I'm not going to do that. I'm
going to coach these guys, watch them
move around, get to know them, see what
they can do, see what they can process,
and then we're going to build the scheme
around the players.
>> Sure. How do you go about establishing
that right away?
>> I think you you you set a standard and
you talk to the players about what the
expectation is and you hold them to it
and you make it very black and white is
these are the things we talked about
together. This is the standard that we
want. These are this is how we're going
to hold each other accountable and then
we're going to hold you to it. It's not
going to be, hey, this is what we say we
want, but then we're going to not show
up on time and we're not going to put in
the extra work and we're not going to do
the little things that we're saying.
That's not how it's going to work. It's
it's going to be a shared vision. And
then my job and our job as coaches is to
hold them to that because if you're
telling me you want to be up here and be
this great, okay, well, this is what
we're going to do. We're going to sit
down and have that conversation. And
then don't get mad at me when it's 110
degrees and you don't feel like doing it
anymore. I'm going to make you do it
because you told me when you were
comfortable in this meeting room in air
conditioning that that's what you wanted
and I'm going to remind you of that. And
I think that's a really good example is
tell me how great you want to be. Tell
me what your goals are. I'm going to do
everything in my power. So you better be
on time or then you're full of it.
That's not what you want. And then be
very direct and honest with the players
and and don't give them any gray area.
And I think the players, all the great
ones that I've been around, they respect
that. And it's not like a demeaning
thing at all. It's I'm gonna be
demanding and I'm not gonna demean them.
I'm just gonna push them because they're
gonna want to be great.
I'm not worried about how anyone views
anything. I mean, all I'm excited for is
getting our players here. I mean, that's
I mean, we got here two months ago. We
haven't really been around any of our
players, so we get them in a week. We
have some really good pieces on the
team. We brought in some free agents. We
have the draft coming up. Um, I just I'm
not thinking in those terms. All I'm
doing is excited to get these players
here and do everything possible to get
them better to win games. I mean, that's
that's how my mind works.
>> What have you
say?
>> Yeah. Do everything in your power like
any other player to show us that you are
the best player at your position and
then our job is to play the best player
to win games. And that's it's exactly
what I would say to Quinn. Um I like
Quinn. Quinn's one of the first guys
that reached out to me when I got the
job. Um I thought Quinn did a really
good job at the end of the year, but I
would say that to any player. I mean, go
out there and work. Do everything in
your power to improve. Take the
coaching, learn to scheme, and
show us and show the team that you're
the best player, and our job is to play
you. Um
so that is exactly what I would tell
him.
Um, I'm not really sure I've looked at
it like that to be honest with you. Um,
you know, like I said, I I really do and
I mean this and I would I said this to
you from the beginning. We we have some
pieces already that I'm excited about
those guys. And am I excited about Yeah.
developing however many draft picks we
end up or guys we end up drafting and
then signing after. Yeah, I can't wait
to do that. Um, but we also have a lot
of guys that we sign that are on
one-year deals that we're going to get
everything they have, too. and I can't
wait to pour into them and try to help
them in their careers. So, it's just
look, I'm just excited to get around
these guys and coach these guys. And I I
feel like we're finally close to that
point, you know? So, it gets uh lonely
in the office after a while when there's
not many players walking around and this
is what we do and this is what I love is
to be around these guys and connect with
these players.
I think it helped. My first goarounds
helped a lot. Um whether it was hiring a
staff, whether it was delegating, I
wasn't very good at that. My first year
at BC, I thought I could do way more
than I could. Um, it's understanding
that each day you might not accomplish
every single thing that you thought you
could because stuff's going to come up
and you just keep working, you keep
crossing things off and you keep working
and eventually you'll get it done. But,
but I think my experience really helped
me out a lot. Are there surprises? Yeah,
I mean, without being specific, there's
some things that come up every day that
you just got to continue to learn from.
Um, you know, ask questions and just
figure some stuff out as you go. But,
we've got great resources. I've got
great resources. And you know, I'm not
going to tell you that I have all the
answers because I don't. I'm I'm going
to learn and get better every single day
and do the best that I can.
>> You move back into obviously the
experience at BC. What did you take away
from that those two years in terms of
building a culture, building
>> my time at BC?
>> Oh, no. With Green Bay.
>> I learned a lot from Matt. Um
Matt does such a good job of holding the
players accountable. Kind of like what
we were just we were just talking about.
He defines a standard and and he holds
him to it and and I respect that a ton
about Matt. Um just I learned a lot
about what helped me was seeing Matt as
the offensive coordinator and the head
coach and the way he sets everything up
for me to now be the head coach and the
defensive coordinator. That has helped
me a lot. The way Matt handled that in
the offseason and was able to kind of
like, you know, let Steno kind of do a
lot in the offseason so he could really
be the head coach. I learned a lot from
him in that regard. Um, but I've learned
a ton a ton from Matt. I have so much
respect for him, how he treats people,
how he how he treats the staff, how he
pushes the staff, how he holds his staff
accountable, and his expectations, not
just for the players, but for the staff.
Because the one thing about him, I mean,
he works. I mean, Matt's going to be one
of the first guys in, he's going to be
one of the last to leave. I mean,
there's times when it's like no one's in
the office like, Matt, what are you
still doing there? But I have so much
respect for him because of that, because
all he wants to do is win. And I um I'm
just so grateful that Matt gave me the
opportunity to come back to the NFL. I
mean, because he changed my life, right?
I mean, he gave me the opportunity to
come back and now all of a sudden I'm a
head coach again. So, not only do I love
him as a person, but I think he's one of
the best coaches in our league.
I just think what Caleb did at the end
of the games um and his ability to make
off-scheduled plays
was incredible. I mean I I mean that's
just me being honest. Um at the end of
the games when he had to make
off-scheduled plays and somehow pull it
off, he did. So he got better throughout
the season. I think he's I think he's a
really good quarterback that's only
gonna get better.
>> Say that again.
>> You just got to be on it until the end
of the game. But that that's the NFL. I
mean, every single game,
look, every time every time I was in the
heads on the booth, whether we were up
big or whether we were down, I I would
tell everybody, guys, this this game's
going to come down to the end of the
game, everybody just keep doing your
thing. That's our league. I mean, and
when you get guys who are really good
like that, you got to make sure you're
on it.
curious.
>> Yeah, I don't know anything about report
cards or so that's I got no idea what
what that would be all about.
All my interactions with the players and
Matt, I mean, I think Matt did it the
right way. He told guys the truth. He
told them where they stand. Sometimes um
sometimes guys are just not going to be
happy with their role I guess. So I'm
not sure where that's coming from.
>> You said one of the best.
>> Uh I I have no idea. I mean, like I
said, what Matt has done in this league
from the time that he got in this league
and his win percentage and what he's
done at Green Bay, I mean, guy's had one
of the best careers. I mean, he deserves
to be the head coach of the Green Bay
Packers. Um, and it wouldn't surprise me
if they continue to take steps and
eventually he gets himself a Super Bowl.
I think we we got to draft the best
players possible. Um and then whoever
they are, we'll coach them up and and
we'll make it work. How do I What was
your second part?
>> I like them. Um at the same time, I
really haven't been around them in
person as much. So, we'll find out what
they can do soon. It's all going to come
down to once we get these players on the
field. You know, I've just met some. I
barely talked to three quarters of the
team. So, it's going to be a big couple
weeks coming up.
>> You're probably going to add some bars
in the draft.
You have
kind of random, but you weren't here
last year. The whole year we kept asking
about why
guard right in college. Just curious
guys.
I just think once we get these guys and
figure out what they can do, whether
he's better on the right, whether he's
better on the left, I think after OTAAS
and as we get into training camp, we'll
figure all that out. But for me to give
you any answer right now, truthfully,
I'd just be making it up.
>> Lambo,
>> we do come to Lambo.
>> Hopefully week one.
Why is that?
>> What?
>> There's a lot of reasons.
>> There's a couple that I can think of.
>> One of my favorite guys might not be
ready to play by then, too.
Mike, I hope you're ready to play week
one. I really do. And knowing Micah,
he'll probably be ready to play week
one.
>> Definitely.
>> Yeah. I just don't have to be the one.
Uh, someone else has got to hold him to
it, though.
>> It wouldn't surprise me though if he
did.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. I love Dave.
>> Yeah. I'm not looking I'm not looking to
I'm we're going to look to do this our
way. I have so much respect for how the
Packers do things from the top down, but
this is not going to be like we're
trying to recreate anything. What what I
tried to bring to Green Bay was a play
style on defense that we were going to
play harder and more physical and more
violent than everybody that we played.
And that's what I wanted to add to the
Green Bay Packers. And I think for the
most part, if you turned on our tape, we
played pretty hard. So, I want our whole
team here in Miami to play with that
same mindset. This isn't just about me
coaching the defense now. This is about
the culture of every person that touches
that field. That's what I want it to
look like. So, this is not going to be,
yeah, this is how we did it in Green
Bay. I have ton of respect for
everything in Green Bay. I mean, even
these guys, I mean, they've been
unbelievable, but this is now about the
Miami Dolphins and how we're going to do
things.
especially
outside.
>> It's it's it's the people you bring in.
One, as we go through this draft
process, you you want to find out if a
guy loves football or if a guy's going
to be tough and if a guy's going to be
physical, turn the tape on. Don't go
don't ask him. Don't ask one of his
coaches. Don't ask somebody some guy
that scouted him. Turn the tape on. And
if you see a guy running full speed,
putting his face on people, a wide out
blocking downfield, a guard looking to
clean somebody up, I mean, if you see
those things over and over, you're going
to find guys that love football. And
you're going to find guys that are going
to play that way. So, we got to go out
and we got to find guys like that. And
then we got to push them on the field.
When we can be physical, we have to be
physical. Does that mean sometimes there
might be some live work in training
camp? Yeah, there might be. I want to
find out who can play the game of
football. And I've said this before, you
know how you get good at football? You
play football. You know how you get good
at tackling? You tackle and you block
and you get off blocks and you run to
the football and you finish down the
field and then you set a standard where
this is how it's going to look or you're
not playing right. And when you when you
start to build that and create that,
then all the young guys are going to see
it and that's how they're going to
practice. There are restrictions. So as
I say the guys are going to be here in a
week, we can't do that in otaas. It's
it's not a physical deal, but how we
train, how we run to the ball, how we
move, how we attack in the weight room,
that has to be our mindset and
everything that we do. I like that
question because I love talking about
that.
putting together
a little bit earlier.
>> Um, the only thing I'll tell you that's
that it becomes harder is it's just who
can you really get out because there's a
lot of people under contract. Um, and
that's probably the hardest thing.
Everything else you have a plan, you
have a vision, you have to have almost
like a depth chart of I want this guy
and maybe I can't get him. I so you got
to be re really detailed and what I did
this past off season was I created like
a depth chart of coaches and then even
I'll give you an example even after we
played a team and I was like wow I
really that O line coach was really good
I'd go back to my office and I'd put
that guy's name down or if there was a
wide receiver coach that I had a ton of
respect for after coaching against him
I'd put that guy's name down. So I just
tried to build a depth chart in case I
did get a chance to interview. it wasn't
just me going in with two or three
names. So, I think my best advice would
be do your homework, have a big group of
names because you just never know who
you're gonna get because then at the
same time there's like six new coaches
all trying to hire a staff and we're all
trying to hire the same guys. So, that's
the hardest part.
day job, you're going to be my guy. Is
there any?
>> Um, yeah. I mean, there's I don't know
if I've ever promised anyone a job, but
I think as you go through this and you
have friends that or you're really close
with that think all of a sudden because
you got the job that you're going to
hire them. It's hard to tell them you
can't, whether they're not the right
fit, whether this coordinator really
wants this guy. There's so much more
that goes into it than me just saying,
"Yeah, come on. I'm gonna hire you." And
it no one probably understands that
until you sit in this seat.
And I think you just got to be honest
with them. And then you might you might
lose some friends along the way.
Hopefully you don't because they
understand and respect it. But yeah,
I've had those and it's been hard.
>> Can you tell us about that?
>> Uh Bush. Really good interview, really
good recommendations. Bobby came to me
with his name. Um, him and Bobby had had
a lot of conversations. He had been in
the NFL with the Falcons. He had coached
Matt Ryan when he was younger. He had
called plays, which was important to me.
I wanted a guy who had kind of done that
as well. Um, and just again, I'm going
to go back to people, really good
person, really good at connecting with
players. Um, loved his demeanor, and I
think he was excited to get back into
the NFL. So with him and Bobby kind of
in that room, I think they'll be a
really good team together.
>> You guys have an abundance of draft
capital in this class, especially after
the water deal. Can you speak to the
excitement as a head coach and the
opportunity to have that much capital to
work with and early impressions on the
depth of this class?
>> Yeah, I mean, anytime I think you get a
chance to draft players, um, that's
exciting. you know, you're going to have
young guys come in and however many we
wind up with, get a chance to to coach
them and develop them and mold them. So,
yeah, of course, we're excited about
that. I think it's a good draft class.
You know, I've watched a ton of film in
various positions. I I think it's I
think it's very talented.
Well, I think if you got one guy who's
just dominant as an alpha, I think
that's great. And if you don't, you
better have a lot of guys and and do it
together. Um, and if you can do both,
then you got a hell of a group. So, like
I said, I'm excited to see who those
guys are that we have. I think we have
some really good pieces. I think we have
some alphas. And then we'll continue to
see if we can find more.
>> Versatility, athleticism,
um can play the run, can set edges, can
rush, can win quick, have had success in
their careers. Um
>> excited to work with those guys.
Not many situation like this
issues.
How do you feel about this situation?
>> I'm excited. Um, you know, I think John
Eric's done a really good job kicking
this thing off and just excited for the
players to come in. Excited to meet the
the free agents we just signed. Excited
for this draft and I just can't wait to
coach again. Is this easy for you to
play the underdog card? Nobody believes
in this card.
>> I'm not big into playing any cards. I'm
just excited to coach and develop and
and building something fun here.
with Micah. Micah can win anywhere.
>> Put him anywhere and he'll find a way to
win. You can line him up on the outside.
You can put him on the inside. You can
stand him up. You can dictate
protections with him. You can set up
protections where you put a safety and
put them opposite to create one-on-
ones. You can get teams to go five down
and get them one-on- ones.
He Micah doesn't get enough credit for
how smart of a player he is and how he
understands protections and can hear
things and switch up what he does. And
Micah doesn't get enough credit for when
you challenge him to play the run, how
good he is playing the run. So, it's not
hard when you have Micah. You can kind
of just do whatever you want with him.
>> How do you figure out then?
>> Well, it's matchups. It's you have
conversations with them, too. The cool
part about Micah is he'd be in my office
and we'd be sitting there watching film
together and he'd have some great
thoughts and we'd have some great
dialogue and it's Michael, who do you
want to rush against? Do you want that
guard because you think you can beat the
guard? Do you want to go over the center
and just run over the center? Do you
want the tackle? And there's sometimes
Michael wanted the best guy just to beat
him. So, it's conversation. It's game
plan. It's
>> it's a lot of fun.
>> Yeah. Well,
I think again I think it's going to
happen when we get him on the field. I
mean, Chop's had some success. If you
build a a pass rush tape, a Chop, he
does he does things that are like, I
can't wait to get my hands on this guy.
But I think we we need to get to know
him, right? I want to see him live. I
want to see what he looks like in his
stance. I want to see what we can do to
help him out of his stance, out of his
first step. What's his go-to move. Is he
gonna win with speed? What's his
counter? Can we coach him up on that?
Right? Can we help him take the step?
What's his mindset like? Where is he at
right now? Right? So, I just talked to
him on the phone a bunch. I just can't
wait to can't wait to coach him. But he
certainly has that. He his first few
steps, his get off. I mean, he he can he
can roll. I mean, and now it's our job
to coach him up and develop him and and
help him get better.
I love Shawn. Um, what Shawn did with
Jordan, what Shawn did getting Malik
ready. Shawn is a person. Became one of
my closest friends there. Um, one of the
hardest workers that I seen at a younger
age. I mean, always in the building,
always working at it, always one-on-one
with the quarterbacks doing extra thing,
extra things. Um, and he played the
position. So you could say he's only
coached two years, but his time as a
quarterback in the NFL, I mean, all he's
doing is learning football and he's
doing it right. So what he'll bring to
that quarterback room and what he'll
bring to that offense, I mean, I think
he's going to be I think it's going to
be awesome. I I always root for him.
He's He's an He's an awesome guy.
>> You're quick. You like know right when
to jump in. You guys have all noticed
that, too. All right, Joe, go.
Maybe. Do you want a fullback?
>> What do you mean? No. You don't like
playing with
>> fullbacks?
>> Why?
>> You don't like fullbacks either.
>> Does anybody in here?
>> You don't. You just You're not a
fullback guy. Watch. We're gonna bring
in We're gonna We're gonna bring in a
fullback and I'm be like, "Hey, you like
this guy?"
>> Did you have a question?
>> I like fullbacks.
>> I like them all.
>> What kind of help do you think?
>> He'll he'll be a lot of help. He's been
a head coach. He's called plays. He gets
the big picture. Um, one, I love Mike. I
think Mike's going to do an awesome job.
And I love Hackit. I think he's going to
be a big help. Anytime you can have a
guy that sat in that chair and called
plays and he'll be a help for him as a
play caller. He'll be a help for him as
a head coach.
>> Why are you
>> I was with Mike in Cleveland. He was a
QC at the time. I was a DB coach. So, I
got to know him really well. Saw how he
worked a football mind. And I'm just
going to go back to people. I think you
win with people. I think he's I think
he's one of the real good guys in this
league. He's going to treat people the
right way in all aspects. He's going to
be awesome off the field. His wife's
awesome. I love his family. Um, and then
then being with him the second time in
San Francisco, I just saw him grow. Um,
obviously he's been groomed by guys like
Kyle and Shawn, so his football
knowledge is outstanding. And then going
to do it on his own with with Robert,
had some success, had some struggles,
and then to see him come back up, I
think that's an awesome football
journey, and he's been through a lot,
and I I think he's going to be a great
coach.
>> You We'll come back. I don't want you
guys to be mad at each other.
>> I could tell. Well, we'll do it. Fair.
Go.
>> Yeah.
>> He's dynamic. I mean, there's plays that
you're not even blocked right for and he
gets six, seven yards. He his vision,
his acceleration,
the way he can catch the ball out of the
back field. He's so hard to defend. Um,
>> so I'm glad Sully said that.
Why is that?
>> Yeah, it's pretty simple, right? Like
most games it's timing and rhythm and
the ball's out or it's a bad play. When
you're in zone coverage and the
quarterback starts to roam and wide
receivers start to run around, there's
holes everywhere open in zone. When
you're in man coverage and the play goes
off schedule and the quarterback starts
running around, do you know how hard it
is to cover for those extra four, five,
six seconds? I mean, it's it's awful.
Especially if the guy can throw it on
the run. It's just it makes it two parts
to the play that you have to defend. And
then there's the threat of him running,
right? So now your edge guys and your D
line have to play a certain way and make
sure that they don't fly by the
quarterback or you make sure you don't
run a game and now a nose is wrapping to
contain. So you got to call the game
differently the way you kind of run your
games, the way you pressure and then
certain coverages you got to play. Um
so that's why